<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Kaumil Trivedi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Kaumil Trivedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Hybrid Binary Classifier for Pattern Classification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/binaryclassifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/binaryclassifier/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we propose a hybrid binary classifier which combines a decision tree with a support vector machine. The proposed hybrid model has the advantages of improved accuracy and easy interpretability. The model will be useful for feature selection cum classification tasks in real-world supervised learning problems. Numerical evidence is also provided using 25 standard data sets from various fields to assess the performance of the model. Performance of the proposed hybrid binary classifier is quite better when compared to individual classifiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Structures and Algorithms using Python by IIT Madras</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/nptelpython/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/nptelpython/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Specialization by deeplearning.ai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/deeplearningspecialization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/deeplearningspecialization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning by Stanford University</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/courseramachinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/courseramachinelearning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My interview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/courseramachinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/courseramachinelearning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing by IIT Kharagpur</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/nptelnlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/nptelnlp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 3: Deep Dive (Part 1-Functional)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/pythondeepdive1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/pythondeepdive1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spark and Python for Big Data with PySpark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/udemysparkpython/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/udemysparkpython/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/stanfordstatisticallearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/stanfordstatisticallearning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming Big Data with Apache Spark and Python - Hands On!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/certifications/udemytamingbigdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/certifications/udemytamingbigdata/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Regression techniques on House pricing datasets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/advancedregression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/advancedregression/</guid>
      <description>Performed EDA on the Advanced Regression: House pricing dataset on Kaggle. Examined various properties like normality, skewness, kurtosis as well as performed log transformations and analyzed the differences using a normal probability plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emof_AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/emofai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/emofai/</guid>
      <description>Emof_ai is a web API which takes a sample video as an input, detects all the faces in each frame of the video and performs classfication. It classifies the emotion of the face into 1 of 8 emotions viz anger, disgust, fear, happy, sad, surprise, neutral and none(this is when there are no faces detected in the frame at all and hence none means no emotion detected in the frame at all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/frauddetection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/frauddetection/</guid>
      <description>Performed Exploratory Analysis on fraud detection dataset and tried to find interaction terms. Moreover, compared various classifiers offered by the scikit-learn library. Classifiers used are:
 Support Vector Classifier (with RBF Kernel) Support Vector Classifier (with Linear Kernel) Random Forests Bagging Classifier Logistic Regression KNN Classifier LDA Classifier GaussianNB Classifier DecisionTree Classifier GradientBoosting Classifier XGBoost Classifier Extra Trees Classifier  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Classification of Cancer by Gene Expression Monitoring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/molecularclassification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/molecularclassification/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of the 20 NewsGroup Dataset followed by lemmatization and k-means clustering and non-negative matrix factorization for topic modelling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/topicmodeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/topicmodeling/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of the 20 NewsGroup Dataset followed by lemmatization and k-means clustering and non-negative matrix factorization for topic modelling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
 First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging website</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/flask_microblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/flask_microblog/</guid>
      <description>Established a mechanism for a user to follow different people and have the posts of the followed people on the home page. Established an &amp;ldquo;Explore&amp;rdquo; feature where a user can explore different posts from all the users on the website in a descending order of the post timestamp. Established a &amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo; feature using Elasticsearch where people can search for a keyword and have relevant posts displayed.
Github link: https://github.com/kaumil/flask-blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analyzer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/cnn_sentiment_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/creations/cnn_sentiment_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment Analyzer is a ML model as a service made using Flask micro framework. The task is a binary classification problem where I employed CNNs to have a validation accuracy of 84.73% and validation loss of 0.3624. The application serves 2 pipeline: 1 pipeline where the model versions are trained using the jupyter notebook in the sentiment_analysis subfolder. The second pipeline is the inference pipeline where using a config file, Tensorflow Serving is used to deploy that model on a different docker container.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
